[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这就把我们带到了浏览器。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So that brings us to the browser.
所以浏览器平台非常不安全，
So the browser platform is horribly insecure,
20多年后，我们仍在修复它。
we're still fixing it later after over 20 years.
HTML5通过提供强大的新功能使事情变得更糟，而不是更好
HTML5 made things worse instead of better by providing powerful new capabilities to
攻击者在不减轻任何先前存在的弱点的情况下。
the attacker without mitigating any of the preexisting weaknesses.
然而，它仍然是世界上最好的应用程序交付系统。
And yet it is still the world's best application delivery system.
它比其他任何东西都好，包括设计的系统
It is better than everything else including systems that were designed
在网络之后。
after the Web.
每个人都拒绝学习网络的教训。
Everybody refused to learn the Web's lessons.
因此，Web正确的一件事是，几乎所有其他平台
So one of the things that the Web got right, that virtually every other platform
出了错的是网络无过错的受害者安全模式。
has gotten wrong is the web does not have a blame the victim security model.
系统中非常常见的一件事是，
A very common thing in systems is,
如果一个系统必须做出关于安全性的决定
that if a system has to make a decision about security and
没有足够的信息做出正确的决定，它会询问用户。
does not have enough information to make a correct decision, it will ask the user.
并且它将以用户不能理解的语言询问用户。
And it will ask the user in language that the user cannot understand.
如果用户说不，那么它就失败了。
And if the user says no, then it fails.
如果用户说是，那就是用户放弃他们的安全性的错误。
And if the user says yes, it is the users fault for giving up their security.
这不是一个有效的安全模型，但我们一直看到它。
This is not a valid model of security but we see it all the time.
例如，我最近在Android商店买了一个闹钟。
For example, I recently bought an alarm clock at the Android store.
只有在我买下它之后，我才看了一下许可。
And it was only after I bought it, that I looked at the permissions.
它想要的许可之一是无限制地访问互联网。
And one of the permissions it wanted was unlimited access to the internet.
[听不见]等一下
[INAUDIBLE] Wait a minute,
为什么时钟需要无限制地访问互联网？
why does a clock need unlimited access to the internet?
我现在的选择是，让我的时钟泄漏它能在我的
And my choices are now, to let my clock leak everything it can find in my
设备并发送它，谁知道它在哪里。
device and send it who knows where.
或者我花在时钟上的钱用完了，
Or I'm out the money I spent on the clock, and it's just,
这不是一个好的安全模式。
that's not a good model of security.
所以浏览器做对了，
So the thing that the browser got right,
其他的一切都错了，这就是这个问题的答案。
that everything else got wrong was the answer to this question.
程序代表谁的利益？
Whose interest does the program represent?
从计算开始，人们总是假设一个程序
From the beginning of computing it is always been assumed that a program
表示计算机的所有者，或至少表示帐户的所有者。
represents the owner of the machine or at least the owner of the account.
浏览器说不，程序代表一个站点
And the browser says no, the program represents a site and
站点不一定代表用户。
a site does not necessarily represent the user.
这是绝对正确的。
Which was absolutely right.
而其他人都没有发现这一点。
And nobody else has figured that out.
不幸的是，网络做错了很多其他的事情。
Unfortunately the web got a lot of other things wrong.
网络并没有预料到会涉及更多的兴趣
The web didn't anticipate that there could be more interests involved
在一个页面中不仅仅是用户和站点。
in a page than just the user and the site.
并且恶意的一方可以利用编码约定来注入
And that a malicious party can exploit coding conventions to inject
恶意代码。
malicious code.
并且恶意代码获得了站点的所有权利。
And that malicious code gets all of the rights of the site.
这被称为XSS问题。
This is known as the XSS problem.
稍后我们将更多地讨论XSS。
We'll talk more about XSS in a minute.
但是说到这个，我的意思是，你总是听到人们抱怨安全和
But to ground this, I mean, you're always hearing people whining about security and
所有的问题都是多么可怕。
how terrible all the problems are.
让我们说得具体一点。
Let's get really specific.
在这个XSS攻击中，到底会出什么问题呢？
In this XSS attack, what can actually go wrong?
如果攻击者可以将一些脚本放到您的页面上，他能做什么呢？
What can an attacker do, if he can get some script onto your page?
攻击者可以从世界上的任何服务器请求其他脚本。
The attacker can request additional scripts from any server in the world.
一旦它站稳了脚跟，它只需要大约那么多的文字就可以做到这一点，
Once it gets a foothold, and it only needs about that much text in order to do that,
然后它可以获得它想要的所有脚本。
it can then obtain all of the scripts it wants.
浏览器有一个称为同源策略的安全策略，该策略限制
Browsers have a security policy called the same origin policy which limit
浏览器从其他服务器获取数据的能力，但没有限制
the ability of the browser to get data from other servers but there is no limit
关于你可以从世界上最邪恶的服务器上加载多少程序。
at all on how much program you can load from the most evil server in the world.
攻击者可以读取文档。
An attacker can read the document.
攻击者可以看到用户可以看到的一切，
The attacker can see everything the user can see,
甚至是用户看不到的东西。
and even things the user can't see.
攻击者可以看到注释和隐藏字段、cookie
The attacker can see comments and hidden fields, cookies,
我们传输到浏览器的所有东西，攻击者都可以访问。
everything we transmit to the browser, the attacker gets access to.
攻击者可以请求您的服务器和
The attacker can make requests of your server and
您的服务器无法检测到该请求不是由您的应用程序发出的。
your server cannot detect that the request did not originate with your application.
如果您使用SSL，并且
If you're using SSL, and
您应该这样做，攻击者可以访问您的安全连接。
you should, the attacker gets access to your secure connection.
如果您的服务器接受SQL查询，则攻击者可以访问您的数据库。
If your server accepts SQL queries then the attacker gets access to your database.
现在，如果您的服务器正在基于信息构造SQL查询
Now if instead your server is constructing SQL queries based on information
它从浏览器获得的信息，那么您可能只提供访问权限，
that it gets from the browser, then you're only probably giving access,
向攻击者发送到您的数据库，这是因为SQL针对
to the attacker to your database and that's because SQL was optimized for
SQL注入攻击。
SQL injection attacks.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Thank you.
[笑]攻击者已经
[LAUGH] An attacker has
控制显示器并可以向用户请求信息
control over the display and can request information from the user and
用户无法检测到请求不是源自您的应用程序。
the user cannot detect that the request did not originate with your application.
所以现代浏览器有反网络钓鱼的Chrome。
So modern browsers have anti-phishing chrome.
不幸的是，大多数用户并没有注意到这一点。
And unfortunately most users don't pay any attention to that.
但是如果他们关注它，在这种情况下，浏览器会说，它是
But if they are paying attention to it, in this case, the browser is saying, it's
很好，因为浏览器关心的是HTML从何而来。
good, because all the browser's concerned with is where did the HTML come from.
浏览器不会注意脚本是从哪里来的。
The browser doesn't pay any attention to where did the script come from.
脚本可能来自任何地方，而且
And the script could have come from anywhere, and
造成损坏的是脚本，而不是HTML。
the script is what's gonna cause the damage, not the HTML.
所以在一些网站上知道这一点，每当危险的事情即将发生时，
So knowing this on some sites, whenever something dangerous is about to happen,
他们将要求用户再次键入他们的密码。
they will ask the user to type their password again.
理论上，只有用户才会知道密码。
And the theory is that only the user will know the password.
这样，我们就可以确信这不会发生。
And that way, we can be confident that this is not going on.
除了攻击者可以控制显示之外。
Except that the attacker has control of the display.
因此攻击者可以询问用户，您的密码是什么？
And so the attacker can ask the user, what's your password?
浏览器说，很好，告诉他。
And the browser was saying, good tell him.
所以如果你运营这些网站之一，要求人们重新识别
So if If you're operating one of these sites which asks people to re-identify
在不太可能的时候，你实际上正在做的是训练你的
themselves at unlikely times, what you're actually doing is training your
用户在攻击者得到密码的那一刻就放弃他们的密码
users to give up their passwords the instant the attacker gets
控制。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么
control. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then
攻击者可以将信息发送到世界上任何地方的服务器。
the attacker can send information to servers anywhere in the world.
他们通过抓取页面，通过与用户交谈所学到的一切，
Everything that they learned by scraping the page, by talking to the user,
通过查询您的数据库，
by querying your database,
然后他们可以把这个发送到这个星球上最邪恶的服务器上。
they can then send this to the most evil server on the planet.
同样，浏览器具有相同的源策略，该策略限制了它们的
Again, the browser has a same origin policy which limits their
能够从其他服务器接收数据，但
ability to receive data from other servers but
它没有限制他们发送所有这些被盗信息的能力。
it puts no limit on their ability to send all of these stolen information.
那么，浏览器，这是不是开始吓坏任何人了？
So, and the browser, is this starting to freak anybody out?
因为我们为什么要在这个平台上做生意？
Because why are we doing business on this platform?
是不是有人-&gt；&gt；扬声器3：[听不见]我只是有点
Is that anyone- &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [INAUDIBLE] I just kind of
世界课程中有什么。
what's in the world course.
道格拉斯·克罗克福德(Douglas Crockford)：不，
Takes care of all this for us right? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No, no,
没人会拿走的。&gt；&gt；演讲者3：我真的在等
nobody's taking it. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I'm really waiting for
你给我解释一下，我不知道。
you to explain to me, I don't know.
在哪里，我想知道我在做什么。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我想我是
Where, I wanna know what I'm doing. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I think I'm
说清楚了。
making it clear.
无论如何，但浏览器不会阻止任何这些。
Anyway but the browser does not prevent any of these.
Web标准需要这些弱点。
Web standards require these weaknesses.
如果你要从头开始建立一个新的网络浏览器。
If you were to build a new web browser from scratch.
如果它没有让你和你的客户接受所有这些
If it didn't subject you and your customers to all of these
潜在的问题，它将不符合标准。
potential problems, it would not be standards compliant.
一次成功的攻击的后果是可怕的，
And the consequences of a successful attack are horrible,
有对客户的伤害或失去信任，有法律责任。
there's harm to customers or loss of trust, there are legal liabilities.
现在甚至有关于过失的刑事责任的讨论，因为
There's even talk now about criminal liabilities for negligence, for
允许人们的身份被盗。
allowing people to have their identity stolen.